Doug Leinen

Web Development Engineer

daleinen@gmail.com | 773.992.6588 | Chicago IL, 60626

dougleinen.com github.com/daleinen7

I am a software engineer trained in Full-Stack development. My years of experience in audio, design, and team management allow me to bring additional perspectives to my programming work. That along with 6 years of experience building websites as a freelancer has prepared me to transition my passion for development to a full-time career.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Remote: July 2020 - Present

- **Teaching Assistant** Coach students on problem-solving skills, best practices, and general debugging since March 2021
- **Student** Full-stack program conducted remotely, providing experience with current languages, tools, and methodologies 3 months July-October 2020

Code for Chicago: December 2020 - Present

- Collaborate with a cross-functional team using Kanban and Weekly Stands
- Write clean code for CfC website and Voma (volunteer management system)
- Provide code reviews and draft documentation for team members

Candy Fluffs: March 2021 - June 2021

- Utilized Gatsby, Snipcart, and DatoCMS to build a functional e-shop
- Managed a team of two other developers
- Ensured best practices, ally and SEO

Good's Fine Picture Framing, Evanston IL: 2016 - 2020

- **Store Manager** Supervised a team to ensure timely completion of conservation and display-minded picture framing. Brought the redo percentage down 30% from previous years 1 year
- **Production Manager** Oversaw transition from a paper system to digital as well as maintained day to day production department operations 2 years
- Designer/Fitter Brought projects from design to execution for high-end clientele - 1 year

SKILLS

Languages:

Javascript HTML CSS Typescript Python Ruby PHP

Web Development:

SEO Jamstack Serverless ally (Web Accessibility) Remote Collaboration Git / Github

Tools / Databases:

React Gatsby NextJS SASS EJS Styled Components jQuery Bootstrap GraphQL REST MongoDB PostgreSQL DynamoDB HeadlessCMS MySQL AWS/S3 Express Heroku Netlify

General:

Management Customer Service Mentorship Basic Design Principles Digital Imaging

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive: 2020 – Software Engineering

Conservatory of Recording Arts & Sciences: 2006 – Audio Engineering **lowa Western Community College:** 2002-2004 – Design and Photography